<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Learning with Rick</title>
    <link>https://rickt.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Learning with Rick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rickt.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform for ECS/EC2</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/10-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/10-terraform/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Today I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my experience of learning the basics of Terraform. I will show how I used it to set up AWS infrastructure to run the FastAPI backend of my notes app. Namely, I will be setting up an ECS cluster with one EC2 provider. I will also share some of the struggles I had to overcome - at least the ones I haven&amp;rsquo;t suppressed.
Setup First, I installed Terraform using the [official guide from Hashicorp], using the following commands for my Linux machine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Balancing Using Nginx and Docker</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/09-load-balancing-a-fastapi-app-with-nginx-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/09-load-balancing-a-fastapi-app-with-nginx-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In my ongoing effort to learn DevOps tools and practices, today I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my experience setting up scaling for the FastAPI back end of my notes app, using Docker&amp;rsquo;s Compose feature as well as setting up the incredibly common webserver, Nginx, as a load balancer.
Setup To get started, I made a new git branch of my project&amp;rsquo;s repo. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t super necessary since this is a relatively simple project that I alone work on, but I wanted to get more practice with an important part of the git ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up GitHub Actions to Deploy to ECS</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/08-setting-up-github-actions-to-deploy-to-ecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/08-setting-up-github-actions-to-deploy-to-ecs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was excited to tackle today&amp;rsquo;s topic of using a CI/CD tool, GitHub Actions, to automate part of the deployment of my Notes app. One of my favorite aspects of working with technology is getting to automate things. Much of what I built in my last post was done manually in a graphical interface, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t as exciting for me, but was a necessary step in the learning process. So, let&amp;rsquo;s see how I automated part of the deployment process using GitHub Actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a FastAPI Container to AWS ECS</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/07-deploying-fastapi-to-aws-ecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/07-deploying-fastapi-to-aws-ecs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In my latest efforts to learn more about DevOps tools and practices, I set out to deploy the Docker image for my FastAPI app API to AWS. You can read about the process of building the image in my last post.
Initially, I was overwhelmed by the many ways to run containers on AWS. I mistakenly decided to try Lambda - partially to use the most &amp;ldquo;serverless&amp;rdquo; method I could, but mostly to be as cheap as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containerize a FastAPI App with Docker</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/06-containerize-a-fastapi-app-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/06-containerize-a-fastapi-app-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In my ongoing effort to learn the tools and practices for DevOps engineering, today I wanted to containerize the FastAPI backend of the notes app that I created previously, using Docker.
Getting Started I started off by creating a Dockerfile. Well, I really started off by questioning whether my flat folder structure was best practice (it clearly isn&amp;rsquo;t), but decided that it would be better to focus my attention on the learning task at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing CSV Data Using Python</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/05-parsing-csv-data-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/05-parsing-csv-data-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently had another use case for writing a script to parse some data. Normally, I would use Powershell for something like this (see Updating a CSV using Powershell), but this time I wanted to challenge myself to do it in Python. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Python a little, but I&amp;rsquo;m not as strong with it as I am with Powershell.
The problem I wanted to solve was that I needed to take a pool of digital cards for my MTG Cube, sort them into their color categories, shuffle the color-grouped cards, and deal them into &amp;ldquo;booster packs&amp;rdquo; - groups of 15 cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Notes App with FARM Stack</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/04-creating-a-basic-notes-app-using-the-farm-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/04-creating-a-basic-notes-app-using-the-farm-stack/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to learn more about CI/CD tools and techniques. To do this I could use an existing project, but I also want to get more reps in with the development process, so I decided to start a new project. A note taking app sounded interesting and simple enough to cover what I want to learn. So, I started by setting up a basic structure using the FARM stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating a CSV Using Powershell</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/03-updating-a-csv-using-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/03-updating-a-csv-using-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I love Powershell. Over my IT career I have spent a lot of time learning how to use it to automate all kinds of things: batch creation of Active Directory accounts, interfacing with APIs, tracking network congestion, and conducting mass software deployments. During the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been focused on learning DevOps practices, where Linux is king and Powershell is rarely mentioned - and I&amp;rsquo;ve missed using it.
Fortunately, I had a use case recently where Powershell would be a great tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Website to S3 Using AWS CLI</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/02-deploying-a-website-to-s3-using-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/02-deploying-a-website-to-s3-using-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A while back I built a basic CRUD app to learn more about app development. For a while I hosted it on an EC2 instance, but shut it down at some point. To get it back up an running I decided to split the front end hosting off and use S3.
I had set up a simple website on S3 using the graphical interface before, so this time I wanted to challenge myself by using the command line with AWS CLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for Home Services</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/01-docker-for-home-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/01-docker-for-home-services/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Up to this point, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used Docker very much. The organizations I worked at were traditional Windows environments with no in-house development. I could see the value in containers generally, but it was hard to justify and especially to convince others it was worth using in those environments.
I&amp;rsquo;ve long hosted various services for myself at home. In the past these were ran on separate Windows VMs so that I could better learn the skills needed for the work I was doing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
