<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Learning with Rick</title>
    <link>https://rickt.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Learning with Rick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rickt.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a new project with FARM stack</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/04-setting-up-a-new-project-with-farm-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/04-setting-up-a-new-project-with-farm-stack/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to learn more about CI/CD tools and techniques. To do this I could use an existing project, but I also want to get more reps in with the development process, so I decided to start a new project. A note taking app sounded interesting and simple enough to cover what I want to learn. So, I started by setting up a basic structure using the FARM stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating a CSV using Powershell</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/03-updating-a-csv-using-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/03-updating-a-csv-using-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I love Powershell. Over my IT career I have spent a lot of time learning how to use it to automate all kinds of things: batch creation of Active Directory accounts, interfacing with APIs, tracking network congestion, and conducting mass software deployments. During the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been focused on learning DevOps practices, where Linux is king and Powershell is rarely mentioned - and I&amp;rsquo;ve missed using it.
Fortunately, I had a use case recently where Powershell would be a great tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a website to S3 using AWS CLI</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/02-deploying-a-website-to-s3-using-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/02-deploying-a-website-to-s3-using-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A while back I built a basic CRUD app to learn more about app development. For a while I hosted it on an EC2 instance, but shut it down at some point. To get it back up an running I decided to split the front end hosting off and use S3.
I had setup a simple website on S3 using the graphical interface before, so this time I wanted to challenge myself by using the command line with AWS CLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for home services</title>
      <link>https://rickt.io/posts/01-docker-for-home-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rickt.io/posts/01-docker-for-home-services/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Up to this point, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used Docker very much. The organizations I worked at were traditional Windows environments with no in-house development. I could see the value in containers generally, but it was hard to justify and especially to convince others it was worth using in those environments.
I&amp;rsquo;ve long hosted various services for myself at home. In the past these were ran on separate Windows VMs so that I could better learn the skills needed for the work I was doing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
